<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1"
	xmlns:ds="eml://ecoinformatics.org/dataset-2.1.1"
	xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.1"
	xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1  
	http://nis.lternet.edu/schemas/EML/eml-2.1.1/eml.xsd" 
	packageId="knb-lter-nwt.98.10" 
	system="knb" 
	scope="system">
	<access authSystem="knb" order="allowFirst" scope="document">
		<allow>
			<principal>uid=NWT,o=lter,dc=ecoinformatics,dc=org</principal>
			<permission>all</permission>
		</allow>
		<allow>
			<principal>public</principal>
			<permission>read</permission>
		</allow>
	</access>
<dataset>
	<title>Snow cover profile raw data for Niwot Ridge and Green Lakes Valley, 1993 - ongoing.</title>
	<creator>
		<individualName>
			<givenName>Mark</givenName>
			<surName>Williams</surName>
		</individualName>
		<address>
		<deliveryPoint>INSTAAR, University of Colorado</deliveryPoint> 
		<deliveryPoint>1560 30th Street</deliveryPoint> 
		<deliveryPoint>UCB 450</deliveryPoint> 
		<city>Boulder</city> 
		<administrativeArea>CO</administrativeArea> 
		<postalCode>80309-0450</postalCode>
	</address> 
		<phone phonetype="voice">(303) 492-8830</phone> 
		<electronicMailAddress>mark.williams@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>
	</creator>
	<metadataProvider>
		<organizationName>Niwot Ridge LTER</organizationName>
		<positionName>Information Manager</positionName>
		<address>
		<deliveryPoint>INSTAAR, University of Colorado</deliveryPoint>
		<deliveryPoint>1560 30th Street</deliveryPoint>
		<deliveryPoint>UCB 450</deliveryPoint>
		<city>Boulder</city>
		<administrativeArea>CO</administrativeArea>
		<postalCode>80309-0450</postalCode>
		<country>USA</country>
	</address>
		<phone phonetype="voice">303-492-2594</phone> 
		<electronicMailAddress>lternwt@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>
		<onlineUrl>http://niwot.colorado.edu/</onlineUrl>
	</metadataProvider>
	<associatedParty id="12010" system="FLS" scope="system"> 
		<individualName>
			<givenName>Mark</givenName>
			<surName>Williams</surName> 
		</individualName> 
		<address>
		<deliveryPoint>INSTAAR, University of Colorado</deliveryPoint> 
		<deliveryPoint>1560 30th Street</deliveryPoint> 
		<deliveryPoint>UCB 450</deliveryPoint> 
		<city>Boulder</city> 
		<administrativeArea>CO</administrativeArea> 
		<postalCode>80309-0450</postalCode>
	</address> 
		<phone phonetype="voice">(303) 492-8830</phone> 
		<electronicMailAddress>hope.humphries@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>
		<role>Data Contact</role> 
	</associatedParty>
	<associatedParty id="12020" system="FLS" scope="system"> 
		<organizationName>Niwot Ridge LTER</organizationName>
		<positionName>Information Manager</positionName>
		<address>
		<deliveryPoint>INSTAAR, University of Colorado</deliveryPoint>
		<deliveryPoint>1560 30th Street</deliveryPoint>
		<deliveryPoint>UCB 450</deliveryPoint>
		<city>Boulder</city>
		<administrativeArea>CO</administrativeArea>
		<postalCode>80309-0450</postalCode>
		<country>USA</country>
	</address>
		<phone phonetype="voice">303-492-2594</phone> 
		<electronicMailAddress>lternwt@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>
		<onlineUrl>http://niwot.colorado.edu/</onlineUrl>
		<role>Data Contact</role> 
	</associatedParty>	
<pubDate>1993</pubDate>
	<abstract>
		<para>Snow pits were excavated at various locations on Niwot Ridge
			and within the Green Lakes Valley. Temperature and snow density were 
			measured at various depths throughout the snow cover profiles in order
			to characterize the temperature and snow water equivalent (SWE) of the
			snowpack throughout the year. Snow density was measured at 10-cm
			intervals using a 1000-ml cutter. Data on snow grain qualities were
			collected beginning in the 1994-95 snow season.</para>
		<para>NOTE: This LTER data portal display does not contain important maintenance/log information. 
			Please be sure to view the EML file (a text file that contains XML tags) which is included in 
			the zip archive (click on "Download zip archive") for legacy maintenance/log information 
			pertaining to each dataset. The EML file name will have the following format:
			knb-lter-nwt.[3 digit dataset number].[version number].xml. Most web browsers can 
			parse the EML so it's easier to read. Scroll down to the "maintenance" tag.</para>
	</abstract>
<keywordSet>
	<keyword>snow weight</keyword>
	<keyword>snow temperature</keyword>
	<keyword>snow depth</keyword>
	<keyword>snow pit</keyword>
	<keyword>saddle grid</keyword>
	<keyword>snow profile</keyword>
	<keyword>hydrology</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Lake 4</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Lake 5</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Lakes Valley</keyword>
	<keyword>Soddie</keyword>
	<keyword>Navajo bench</keyword>
	<keyword>Martinelli</keyword>
	<keyword>tvan</keyword>
	<keyword>subnivean</keyword>
	<keyword>Albion</keyword>
	<keyword>Ameriflux</keyword>
	<keyword>Niwot Ridge LTER</keyword>
	<keyword>NWT</keyword>
</keywordSet>
	<intellectualRights>
		<section>
			<title>Niwot LTER Data Policy</title>
			<para> The following acknowledgment should accompany any publication or 
				citation of these data: <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para> Logistical support and/or data were provided by the 
							NSF-supported Niwot Ridge (NWT) Long-Term Ecological Research (LTER) 
							project and the University of Colorado (CU) Mountain Research Station (MRS). </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> The user of NWT LTER data agrees to provide proper 
							acknowledgment with each usage of the data. Citation of 
							the name(s) of the investigator(s) responsible for the 
							data set, in addition to the generic statement above, 
							constitutes proper acknowledgment. Author(s) (including NWT investigators) 
							of published material that makes use of previously unpublished 
							NWT data agree to provide the NWT data manager with a PDF of 
							that material as soon as it becomes available. The user of NWT 
							data agrees not to resell or redistribute shared data.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Disclaimer</title>
			<para> The NSF-supported NWT LTER project shall not be held liable for 
				improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained 
				herein, nor assumes liability for misuse, manipulation or distribution 
				of the data. These data  
				are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. 
				The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change 
				over time. The user of these data should be aware that, 
				while efforts have been taken to ensure that these data are of the 
				highest quality, there is no guarantee of perfection for the data 
				contained herein and the possibility of errors exists. It is the 
				responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and 
				in a manner consistent with the limitations of data in 
				general and these data in particular. Users assume responsibility 
				to determine the usability of the dataset. NWT LTER gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to 
				the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is 
				strongly recommended that these data be directly acquired from 
				the NWT LTER server and not indirectly through other sources 
				that may have changed the data in some way. Although these data 
				have been processed successfully on computer systems at CU, no 
				warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of 
				the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, 
				nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. 
				This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and 
				aggregate use with other data.  </para></section>
	</intellectualRights>
<distribution>
	<online>
		<url function="download">http://niwot.colorado.edu/data_csvs/snowprof.mw.data.csv</url>
	</online>
</distribution>
<coverage>
<temporalCoverage>
<rangeOfDates>
<beginDate>
<calendarDate>1993-02-26</calendarDate>
</beginDate>
<endDate>
<calendarDate>2012-12-29</calendarDate>
</endDate>
</rangeOfDates>
</temporalCoverage>
<geographicCoverage>
	<geographicDescription>Study sites were various locations on Niwot Ridge and within
		the Green Lakes Valley. Original data are stored at Research Laboratory #3.
	</geographicDescription>
<boundingCoordinates>
<westBoundingCoordinate>-105.643  </westBoundingCoordinate>
<eastBoundingCoordinate>-105.3753 </eastBoundingCoordinate>
<northBoundingCoordinate>40.0615   </northBoundingCoordinate>
<southBoundingCoordinate>39.9932   </southBoundingCoordinate>
</boundingCoordinates>
</geographicCoverage>
</coverage>
<maintenance>
<description>
<para>
	The documentation section of this file was constructed by Susan Kindig, 
	Rick Ingersoll, and Mark Williams during late May of 1993. Data were 
	added for the period from 26 February through 21 May 1993 and the
	file was put under sccs control.[RCI 1 June 1993] Data for pits 
	excavated on 24, 26, 27, and 28 May 1993 were appended to the data 
	section on 3 June 1993.[RCI 3 June 1993] Data for pits excavated on
	2 and 4 June 1993 were appended to the data section on 8 June 1993.
	[RCI 8 June 1993] Raw data were double-entered using EasyEntry
	programs (see "The Management of NWT LTER Data on the PC") and then
	processed on a Sun SPARC 2 (see "The Management of NWT LTER Data
	on culter").[RCI 14 June 1993] Data for pits excavated on 9 and 11
	June 1993 were appended to the data section on 14 June 1993.
	[RCI 14 June 1993] Data for pits excavated on 16 and 18 June 1993
	were appended to the data section on 24 June 1993.[RCI 24 June 1993]
	Additional comments were added to the documentation section by
	RCI on 13 July 1993. Data for pits excavated on 23 June, 25 June,
	28 June, 9 July, and 12 July 1993 were appended to the data
	section on 13 July 1993.[RCI 13 July 1993] Data for pits excavated
	on 26 July 1993 were appended to the data section on 20 August
	1993.[RCI 20 August 1993] Data for the pit (t3e) excavated on 20
	January 1994 were appended to the data section on 28 January 1994.
	[RCI 28 January 1994] Data for the pit excavated at Saddle grid
	stake 5 on 4 March 1994 were appended to the data section on 
	8 March 1994.[RCI 8 March 1994] Data for the pit excavated at 
	Saddle grid stake 16 on 1 April 1994 were appended to the data 
	section on 5 April 1994.[RCI 5 April 1994] Point identification 
	number 85 for 26 July 1993 was changed to 84 per Mark Williams'
	instructions.[RCI 6 April 1994] Data for the pit excavated at 
	Saddle grid stake 16 on 11 April 1994 were appended to the data
	section on 13 April 1994.[RCI 13 April 1994] Data for the pit
	excavated at Saddle grid stake 16 on 14 April 1994 were 
	appended to the data section on 19 April 1994.[RCI 19 April
	1994] Data for pits excavated on 29 April and 3, 5, and 10 May
	1994 were appended to the data section on 17 May 1994.[RCI 17
	May 1994] The date for the no3 pit excavated on 5 May 1994 was
	corrected (previously was listed as 15 May 1994) and the location 
	code descriptions were updated in the abstract on 17 May 1994.
	[RCI 17 May 1994] Data for pits excavated on 12 and 17 May 1994
	were appended to the data section and an additional site code
	was added to the abstract on 20 May 1994.[RCI 20 May 1994]
	Data for pits excavated on 19 May 1994 were appended to the data 
	section on 23 May 1994.[RCI 23 May 1994] Data for an additional
	pit excavated on 19 May 1994, as well as 3 pits excavated on
	24 May 1994, were appended to the data section on 27 May 1994.
	An additional site code was added to the abstract on that date
	as well.[27 May 1994] Data for pits excavated on 26 May and 1, 2,
	7, and 9 June 1994 were appended to the data section on 14 June
	1994.[RCI 14 June 1994] Data for pits excavated on 16 June 1994
	were appended to the data section on 24 June 1994.[RCI 24 June
	1994] Data for the pit excavated on Arikaree Glacier on 23 June
	1994 were appended to the data section on 1 July 1994.[RCI 1 July
	1994] Data for the pit excavated on Arikaree Glacier on 30 June
	1994 were appended to the data section on 11 August 1994.[RCI 11
	August 1994] Data for the pit excavated on 19 April 1994 was 
	inserted into the data section on 30 August 1994.[RCI 30 August
	1994] Data for the pit (t3e) excavated on 24 January 1995 was 
	appended to the data section on 31 January 1995.[RCI 31 January
	1995] Data for the pit excavated at Saddle grid stake 6 on 24
	January 1995 were appended to the data section on 1 February
	1995.[RCI 1 February 1995] Data for the pit excavated near Saddle
	grid stake 6 on 31 January 1995 were appended to the data section
	on 9 February 1995.[RCI 9 February 1995] Data for the 3 pits 
	excavated on 7 February 1995 were appended to the data section on
	13 February 1995.[RCI 13 February 1995] Data for the 2 pits 
	excavated on 14 February 1995 were appended to the data section
	on 20 February 1995.[RCI 20 February 1995] Data for the 3 pits
	excavated on 21 February 1995 were appended to the data section
	on 1 March 1995.[RCI 1 March 1995] Data for the 2 pits excavated
	on 28 February 1995 were appended to the data section on 13
	March 1995.[RCI 13 March 1995] Data for the pits excavated on
	14 and 21 March 1995 were appended to the data section on 21
	April 1995.[RCI 21 April 1995] Data for a number of pits excavated
	during the period 4 April through 11 May 1995 were appended to
	the data section on 16 May 1995.[RCI 16 May 1995] Data for the t3e
	pit excavated on 10 May 1995 were inserted into the data section
	on 17 May 1995.[RCI 17 May 1995] Data for the pits excavated 
	during the 24 January through 14 February 1995 period were 
	deleted from the data section because there were some errors in
	the original data sheets that had gone uncorrected by field
	personnel prior to entry. The correct data were transcribed onto
	new data sheets and then re-entered and reprocessed. Those data
	were then inserted into this file on 23 May 1995. The data for
	the pit excavated on 15 May 1995 were appended to the data section
	on 23 May 1995, as well.[RCI 23 May 1995] Data for pits excavated
	on 22 and 23 May 1995 were appended to the data section on 30 May
	1995.[RCI 30 May 1995] Data for the pits excavated on 24 and 25 May
	1995 were appended to the data section on 6 June 1995.[RCI 6 June
	1995] Data for the pits excavated on 1 and 2 June 1995 were 
	appended to the data section on 7 June 1995.[RCI 7 June 1995]
	Descriptions for 3 new location codes (ma1-ma3) were added to the 
	comments section on 12 June 1995.[RCI 12 June 1995] Data for the 
	pits excavated on 7 and 8 June 1995 were appended to the data 
	section on 13 June 1995.[RCI 13 June 1995] Data for the 8 June 1995
	006 pit were appended to the data section on 15 June 1995.[RCI
	15 June 1995] Data for the pits excavated on 14, 15, and 22 June
	1995 were appended to the data section on 29 June 1995. Relevant
	comments from the hard-data sheets from 1 February through 22
	June 1995 were added to the comments section on 29 June 1995.
	[RCI 29 June 1995] Data for the pits excavated on 20 and 21 June
	1995 were inserted into the data section on 30 June 1995.[RCI 30
	June 1995] Data for the pits excavated on 5 July 1995 were appended
	to the data section on 10 July 1995.[RCI 10 July 1995] Data for the
	006 pit excavated on 27 June 1995 and the t3e pit excavated on 10
	July 1995 were inserted and appended, respectively, to the data
	section on 19 July 1995.[RCI 19 July 1995] Data for the ark pit
	excavated on 20 July 1995 was appended to the data section on 31
	July 1995.[RCI 31 July 1995] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 19 
	and 26 January 1996 were appended to the data section on 8 February
	1996.[MAH 8 February 1996] Data for the 006 pit excavated on 2
	February 1996 was appended to the data section on 21 February 
	1996.[MAH 21 February 1996] Data for the 006 pit excavated on
	16 February 1996 were appended to the data section on 23 February
	1996.[MAH 23 February 1996] Data for the 006 pit excavated on
	23 February 1996 were appended to the data section on 5 March
	1996.[MAH 5 March 1996] Data for the 006 pit excavated on 8
	March 1996 were appended to the data section on 15 March 1996.[MAH
	15 March 1996] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 15 and 22 March
	1996 were appended to the data section on 9 April 1996.[MAH 9
	April 1996] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 5 and 12 April
	1996 were appended to the data section on 29 April 1996.[MAH 29
	April 1996] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 25 April 1996 and
	3 and 10 May 1996 were appended to the data section on 29 May
	1996.[MAH 29 May 1996] Data for the following pits and dates
	were appended to the data section on 2 July 1996: 23 April 1996 -
	g3s, g3n, g3v, avn, and avv; 24 April 1996 - g4s, g4v, g5v, g5n,
	and g5s; 21 May 1996 - g3n, and 006; 22 May 1996 - g5n, g5v, and
	g5s; 17 May 1996 - 006; 6 June 1996 - 006.[MAH 2 July 1996] Data for
	the g4n pit excavated on 24 April 1996, the 006 pit excavated on
	29 May 1996, and the 006 pit excavated on 13 June 1996 were appended
	to the data section on 22 July 1996.[MAH 22 July 1996] Data (including
	both sets of temperatures) for the sub pit excavated on 28 April 1996
	were appended to the data section on 20 November 1996.[MAH 20 November
	1996] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 21 June 1996, 24 January
	1997, and 7 February 1997 were appended to the data section on 13
	February 1997.[MAH 13 February 1997]. Data for the 006 pit excavated
	on 31 January 1997 were appended to the data section on 24 February
	1997.[MAH 24 February 1997] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 14,
	20, and 28 February 1997 were appended to the data section on 26
	March 1997.[MAH 26 March 1997] Data for the 006 pits excavated on
	7, 14, and 21 March 1997 and 9 and 11 April 1997 were appended to
	the data section on 7 May 1997.[MAH 7 May 1997] Data for the 006
	pit excavated on 18 April 1997 and the sae and saw pits excavated
	on 30 April 1997 were appended to the data section on 19 May 1997.[MAH
	19 May 1997] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 7, 13, 19, and 30
	May 1997 were appended to the data section on 9 June 1997.[MAH 9 June
	1997] Data for the g5n, g5s, 084, and 085 pits excavated on 13 May 1997, 
	the ark and 088 pits excavated on 14 May 1997, and the 006 pits excavated 
	on 9 and 16 June 1997 were inserted and appended to the data section on 
	26 June 1997.[MAH 26 June 1997] Data for the 006 pits excavated on 23
	and 30 June 1997 were appended to the data section on 12 September 1997.[MAH
	12 September 1997] Comments from the hard-copy forms for 1996 and 1997 were 
	inserted into the comments section on 2 October 1997. It was discovered 
	that one of the thermometers used to collect the data from the 006 pit on 
	15 March 1996 was off by one degrees C, so those data were corrected and 
	reprocessed on that date as well.[MAH 2 October 1997] Data for the 006 pits
	excavated on 20 and 27 January 1998 were appended to the data section on
	16 February 1998.[MAH 16 February 1998] Data for the pits excavated on 3, 10, 
	13, 17, 20, 24, and 27 February 1998 and 3 and 10 March 1998 were appended to 
	the data section on 24 March 1998. Data from the 006 pit excavated on 6 May 
	1996 were insterted into the data section at that time as well.[MAH 24 March 
	1998] Data from the pits excavated on 6, 13, 17, and 20 March 1998 were
	appended to the data section on 9 April 1998.[MAH 9 April 1998] Data for the
	pits excavated on 3, 7, 10, 24, and 28 April 1998 were appended to the data
	section on 7 May 1998.[7 May 1998] Data for the pits excavated on 17 April 
	1998, and 6, 13, 14, 19, 20 and 21 May 1998 were appended to the data section 
	on 12 June 1998.[MAH 12 June 1998] Data for the 1, 22, and 30 May 1998 sae
	pits were inserted or appended to the data section on 17 June 1998 as were
	the 006 pits from 29 May 1998 and 4 and 12 June 1998, and the 20 May 1998 
	g5v pit.[MAH 17 June 1998] Data for the g5n pit excavated on 20 May 1998
	were inserted in the data section on 19 June 1998.[MAH 19 June 1998] Data for
	the 006 pits excavated on 14 April 1998 and 22 June 1998 were inserted and
	appended where appropriate to the data section on 6 October 1998.[MAH 6 October 
	1998] Data for the pits excavated on 22 December 1998 (ssw), 15 January 1999
	(ssw), 20 January 1999 (006), and 27 January 1999 (006 and ssw) were appended
	to the data section on 26 February 1999.[MAH 26 February 1999] Data for the 
	pits excavated on 3 February 1999 (ssw), 10 February 1999 (ssw and 006), 17 
	February 1999 (006), 18 February 1999 (ssw), 24 February 1999 (ssw), and 3 
	March 1999 (ssw and 006) were appended to the data section on 21 April 1999.[MAH 
	21 April 1999] Data for 17 March 1999 through 6 June 200 were appended to 
	the data section on 16 August 2000.[MAH 16 August 2000] Data for the swn
	pits from 17 and 31 March 1999 were inserted into the data section on 21
	September 2000.[MAH 21 September 2000] Data for the period from 10
	January 2001 through 18 April 2001 were appended to the data section.
	Inserted comments for 1999, 2000 into the comments section [TMA
	16 May 2001]. Appended 2001 comments to the comment section.[TMA
	11 June 2001] Data for the period from 19 April 2001 to 6 June 2001
	were appended to the data section on 30 July 2001.[TMA 30 July 2001]
	Data for 10December2001 and 19December2001 were appended to the data
	section on 7 February 2002.[TMA 7 February 2002] Data for 31 December
	2001 through 14 February 2002 were appended to the data section on
	18 March 2002.[TMA 18 March 2002] Data for 18 February through 16 May
	2002 were appended to the data section.[TMA 25 September 2002] Data
	for 06 November 2002 through 13 February 2003 were appended on 25
	March 2003.[TMA 25 March 2003] Data for 20 February to 26 March 2003
	were appended to the data section.[TMA 21 April 2003] Data for 03
	April 2003 through 31 December 2003 were appended to the data section
	and data for 13 March 2003 was inserted into the data section.[TMA
	06 February 2004] Data for 02 January 2004 through 07 June 2004
	were appended to the data section.[TMA 19 January 2005] Data for 
	13 January through 21 April 2005 were appended to the data section.
	[TMA 20 May 2005] Data for 29 April 2005 through 13 March 2006 were
	appended to the data section.[TMA 14 July 2006] Appended data for the 
	period 23 March through 06 June 2006.  Inserted data for ssw 16 June 
	2005, ssw 23 February 2006, 006 23 February 2006.[TMA 09 August 2006]
	Data for the ssw pit on 07 June 2004 was inserted, and 13 Dec 2006 through
	11 April 2007 were appended to the data section.[TMA 22 May 2007] Data for
	27 April through 23 May 2007 were appended to the data section.[TMA 08
	September 2007] c1b data were inserted and data for 29 May 2007 through 
	17 June 2008 were appended to the data section.[TMA 21 October 2008] 
	Two data columns were removed because they are values used in calculations
	and are not true values.  These columns were number 8 and 9, which were 
	labeled as: COL8. label=horizon mass, type=real,units=g*m
	COL9. label=horizon*temperature, type=real, units=degrees C*m 
	[TMA 25 February 2010] 006 data for 31 December 2008 through 09 June
	2010 were appended to the data section.[HCH 03 July 2010] Data for 
	December 2008 through December 2009 for all sites except 006 were 
	appended to the data section. Incorrect data for ssw on 15 January 2008
	were replaced.[HCH 29 March 2012] Data for 2010 for all sites except
	006 and December 2010 for 006 were appended to the data section.
	Missing data for ssw 10 December 2008 were inserted into the data section.
	[HCH 30 March 2012] Incorrect weight values were changed to missing (999)
	for the following at top or bottom of snowpit: 087 06/16/94, ark 06/16/94,
	085 05/19/98, ark 05/20/98, 006 06/12/98. Removed redundant line from
	ark 05/08/07. Data for 15 December 2010 for c1b were inserted into the
	data section. Data for 2011 for all sites were appended to the data
	section.[HCH 03 April 2012] All data were edited to replace the date
	format with yyyy/mm/dd.[HCH 04 April 2012] Missing data for 18 May 2007 
	for c1b were inserted into the data section.[HCH 09 April 2012] Missing
	data for 2006 were inserted and 2012 data appended. The title, variables,
	keywords, comments, cols, and data format were edited.[HCH 06 July 2013]
</para>
	<para>begin 26 February 1993, ongoing, weekly to biweekly. </para>
</description>
</maintenance>
	<contact>
		<organizationName>Niwot Ridge LTER</organizationName>
		<positionName>Information Manager</positionName>
		<address>
<deliveryPoint>Institute of Arctic and Alpine Research (INSTAAR)</deliveryPoint>
<deliveryPoint>University of Colorado</deliveryPoint>
<deliveryPoint>1560 30th Street</deliveryPoint>
<deliveryPoint>UCB 450</deliveryPoint>
<city>Boulder</city>
<administrativeArea>CO</administrativeArea>
<postalCode>80309-0450</postalCode>
<country>USA</country>
</address>
		<phone phonetype="voice">303-492-2594</phone> 
		<electronicMailAddress>lternwt@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>
		<onlineUrl>http://niwot.colorado.edu/</onlineUrl>
	</contact>
	<publisher>
		<organizationName>Niwot Ridge LTER</organizationName>
		<positionName>Information Manager</positionName>
		<address>
<deliveryPoint>Institute of Arctic and Alpine Research (INSTAAR)</deliveryPoint>
<deliveryPoint>University of Colorado</deliveryPoint>
<deliveryPoint>1560 30th Street</deliveryPoint>
<deliveryPoint>UCB 450</deliveryPoint>
<city>Boulder</city>
<administrativeArea>CO</administrativeArea>
<postalCode>80309-0450</postalCode>
<country>USA</country>
</address>
		<phone phonetype="voice">303-492-2594</phone> 
		<electronicMailAddress>lternwt@colorado.edu</electronicMailAddress>
		<onlineUrl>http://niwot.colorado.edu/</onlineUrl>
	</publisher>
	<methods>
		<methodStep>
			<description>
				<para>These data were manually entered using an EasyEntry form and
then processed on niwotlter, the NWT LTER workstation.
The value in column 5 (horizon thickness) of the data section is the 
difference between the values in column 3 (height of bottom of horizon 
above soil surface) and column 4 (height of top of horizon above soil 
surface). Horizon mass is the product of the horizon thickness and measured
weight. Horizon*temperature) is the product of horizon thickness and 
measured temperature. These derived values were used to calculate snow water
equivalents (SWE) and depth-weighted mean temperatures for each profile; 
those reduced data can be found at: 
http://niwot.colorado.edu/exec/.extracttoolA?snowateq.mw
Additional data associated with the same snow profiles can be found at
http://niwot.colorado.edu/data_csvs/snochemh.mw.data.csv
http://niwot.colorado.edu/data_csvs/snochemp.mw.data.csv
http://niwot.colorado.edu/data_csvs/snowgran.mw.data.csv
Additional qualitative and quantitative data (e.g. air temperatures,
cloudiness and insolation, wind speed and direction, etc.) were
recorded on the original data collection forms but not included
in this file.</para><para>
It should be noted that snow profile data were used to characterize
snowpack temperatures and water equivalence over large areas.
As snow melted, profile locations were moved. Consequently, there
are instances where total snow depth for a given location code
increased from one date to the next, although no solid
precipitation had been recorded for the period. Large changes 
in total snow depth at a particular location code were often a 
function of minor relocation of the pit in conjunction with the 
rugged topography of the area. </para><para>
Most of the snow profile measurements were made on the Saddle grid
and location codes 001 through 088 refer to snow cover profile data for
grid stakes 1 through 80A, respectively. Location codes of 011 and 012,
for example, would be used for snow profile data collected near grid
stakes 10A and 11, respectively. Additional snow pit locations (and the
respective location codes) were as follows: Saddle N15 site (081),
Martinelli central upper slope - M10 site (082), Martinelli east upper
slope - M19 site (083), south of Green Lake 4 inlet (084), north of Green
Lake 4 inlet (085), Green Lake 4 outlet (086), Green Lake 5 (087), 50m
south of creek on Navajo bench (088), Martinelli M2 (089), slightly
different Navajo location than 088 (090), snowfence thermistor #3 east
(t3e), N15 Saddle site control pit (nco), N15 Saddle site 15nitrate
addition pit (no3), N15 Saddle site 15ammonium addition pit (nh4),
Arikaree Glacier site (ark), 10 m west of subnivean lysimeter (sub), 
15 m south of subnivean lysimeter and 3 m south of Watershed fence (ssb),
Martinelli snow drift near road (ma1), Martinelli snow drift 5 m west of 
Martinelli permanent plot 31 (ma2), Martinelli snow drift at maximum 
convexity (ma3), Green Lake 5 north facing slope (g5n), Green Lake 5
valley floor (g5v), Green Lake 5 south facing slope (g5s), Green Lake
4 valley floor (g4v), Green Lake 4 south facing slope (g4s), Green Lake
3 north facing slope (g3n), Green Lake 3 valley floor (g3v), Geen Lake
3 south facing slope (g3s), Albion Village north facing slope (avn),
and Albion Village valley floor (avv), east edge of subalpine subnivean
lysimeter field (sae), west edge of subalpine subnivean lysimeter field
(saw) 300 meters east of T-van towards the subalpine subnivean (t30),
south-west of subalpine subnivean lysimeter field (ssw), new site at west 
edge of subalpine subnivean (swn), Green lake 5 south facing outlet (5os),
near C-1 Ameriflux tower[~15m northwest of tower] (hydRA),
near C-1 Ameriflux tower[~25m west of tower]: tower tree well 1(tw1),
tower tree well 2 (tw2), tower meadow 1 (tm1), tower meadow 2 (tm2),
C1 bowling (c1b), southwest of soddie lysimeter field (ssw), Ameriflux
tree B-(AB1) index 10 cm from tree (ab1), 50 cm from tree (ab2),
100 cm from tree (ab3), 150 cm from tree (ab4), 200 cm from tree (ab5),
250 cm from tree (ab6), Ameriflux tree 1-(A11) index 10 cm from tree (ab11), 
50 cm from tree (ab12), 100 cm from tree (ab13), 150 cm from tree (ab14), 
200 cm from tree (ab15), 250 cm from tree (ab16), northeast of soddie, 
shallow (nes), north mid soddie (nom), northeast mid soddie (nem).</para><para>
For the 20 January 1994 t3e profile, the 10-40 cm horizons were
too hard for density measurements and the net weights for each
of the 3 10-cm horizons was estimated as 450 g.</para><para>
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 31 January
1995 near Saddle grid point 6 indicated that the location was "~30 m
north of the subnivean shelter (~20 m east of the prev. site [006])".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 18 April
1995 at location code ssb indicated that the horizons from 200 to 240
cm above ground represented new snow.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 18 April
1995 near Saddle grid point 6 indicated that the horizons from 150 to
180 cm above ground represented new snow.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 25 April
1995 at location code t3e indicated that there was new snow and/or
blown snow.
Notes on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 4 May 1995
at location code ssb indicated that there was new snow and that 
there were no data for the horizons from 0 to 70 cm above the ground.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 11 May
1995 at location code 084 indicated that there was "all new snow
since Apr 9".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 15 May
1995 at location code 006 indicated that the soil was not frozen.
Notes on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 22 May
1995 at location code nh4 indicated that "soil frozen but at O
[degrees] C", "string where tracer applied at 100 cm", "1 cm
saturated layer at bottom of pack", and "melt just starting".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 23 May
1995 at location code 006 indicated that the soil was not frozen.
Notes on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 25 May
1995 at location code t3e indicated that liquid water was present
from approximately 130 to 285 cm above the ground and that the
soil was mostly frozen.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 1 June
1995 at location code nco indicated that the tracer thread was at
90 cm.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 1 June
1995 at location code 006 indicated that the soil was unfrozen at
the surface.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 2 June
1995 at location code 084 indicated that the ground was frozen.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 8 June
1995 at location code t3e indicated that the ground was frozen.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 8 June
1995 at location code 006 indicated that there was free water at
ground and that ground was unfrozen at the surface.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 14 
June 1995 at location code 006 indicated that the temperatures
for the horizons 170 to 190 cm above the ground were measured
between ice lenses.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 14 
June 1995 at location code 013 indicated that there was free
water on the soil surface.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 15
June 1995 at location code 087 indicated that height was above
a saturated layer 120 cm deep.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 21 June
1995 at location code t3e indicated that there was free water in the 
horizon 0 to 10 cm above the ground.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 22
June 1995 at location code ark indicated that "bottom is at
least 70 cm above ground".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 20 July
1995 at location code ark indicated that "25-0 cm mixed rock and
snow (no dens., T degrees, or chem. meas. possible)".</para><para>
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 16 January
1996 at location code 006 indicated that there was fresh snow.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 26 January
1996 at location code 006 indicated that there was fresh snow.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 23 February
1996 at location code 006 indicated that there was new snow.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 15 March
1996 at location code 006 indicated that there was new snow.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 23 April 
1996 at location code g3n indicated that the suface temperature was 
-3 degrees C.
Notes on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 23 April 1996
at the location code avv indicated that there was an ice lens 1/4
inch thick at horizon 150 to 160 cm above ground and an ice lens 2 
inches thick at horizon 170 to 180 cm above ground.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 24 April 1996
at the location code g4s indicated that there was an ice lens 1/4
inch thick at horizon 140 to 150 cm above ground.
Notes on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 24 April 1996
at the location code g5s indicated that the real snow depth was "4+ m",
and that the horizon 100 to 110 cm above the bottom of the measured
pit there was an ice lens 10 cm thick (5 cm wet and 5 cm ice).
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 24 April 1996
at the location code g5v indicated that there was an ice lense at the
horizon 140 to 150 cm above ground.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 24 April 1996
at the location code g5n indicated that the ground temperature of
-4.2 degrees C was measured under the first talus rock layer.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 25 April 1996
at the location code 006 indicated that the observers did not get to
the bottom of the pit (the farthest they got was at horizon 30 to 40cm
above the ground).
Notes on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 17 May 1996 at
the location code 006 indicated that there was free water at the ground
surface and a saturated layer 5 cm thick, and that there were larger
grain sizes at the horizons 0 to 80 cm above the ground.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 22 May 1996 at 
the location code g5s indicated that there was an ice lens 10 cm thick
at the horizon 190 to 200 cm above the ground.
Two sets of temperature were taken for the sub pit excavated on 28 
April 1996. The second set of temperatures (with the same corresponding 
weight data, height data, etc. as the initial temperature set) is 
appended directly below the initial set. Notes on the hard-copy form for 
this pit indicated that at horizon 1.0 to 1.1 m above the ground, the first 
temperature taken was between two ice lenses and the second temperature 
taken was above the merged lenses. The notes also indicate that there was 
an ice lens 1.5 m thick between 1.48 to 1.495 m above the ground, that 
there were 1 cm thick ice lenses between 1.54 to 1.55 m, 2.22 to 2.23 m, 
and 2.48 to 2.49 m above ground, that there were 3 cm thick ice lenses 
between 2.76 and 2.79 m and 2.84 and 2.87 m, and that there was a merging 
ice lense between 1.45 to 1.46 m above the ground.
Notes on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 29 May 1996 at the 
location code 006 indicated that there was hail at the horizon 167 to 
175 cm above ground, and new snow at the horizon 175 to 220 cm above ground.</para><para>
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 7 February 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was -9 
degrees C and the ground temperature was -1 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 14 February 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was -14
degrees C and the ground temperature was -1 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 20 February 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was -14
degrees C and the soil temperature was -1.5 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 28 February 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was -3
degrees C and the ground temperature was -4 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 7 March 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was 
3 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 21 March 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was 
-1.5 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 11 April 1997
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was 
-6 degrees C and the ground temperature was -1.5 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 30 April 1997
at the location code sae indicated that the ground was unfozen.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 30 April 1997
at the location code saw indicated that the ground was unfozen.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 7 May 1997 at 
the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was 
0 degrees C.
Notes on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 13 May 1997 at
the location code g5n indicated that the surface temperature was 0
degrees C, and that all depths were relative to the bottom of the
pit not the ground. The probed depth of the snow was 320 cm.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 13 May 1997 
at the location code g5s indicated that the horizon 0 to 10 cm above 
ground was saturated with water, and that there was ice at the bottom.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 13 May 1997 at 
the location code 084 indicated that the surface temperature was 0 
degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 13 May 1997 at 
the location code 085 indicated that the surface temperature was 0 
degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 14 May 1997 at 
the location code 088 indicated that the surface temperature was 0 
degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 30 May 1997 at 
the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was -.5 
degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 9 June 1997 at
the location code 006 indicated that the soil was unfrozen up to a depth
of 8 cm.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 16 June 1997 at
the location code 006 indicated that the bottom 2 cm was saturated
slush/ice mixture, and that the soil was unfrozen to a depth of 9 cm.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 23 June 1997 at 
the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was 0 
degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 30 June 1997 at
the location code 006 indicated that there was approximately .5 cm of
frozen meltwater at the soil/snow interface.</para><para>
A note on the hard-copy form for the sae pit excavated on 10 April 1998
read "recalibrated thermometer - corrected by + 1/4 degree".
A note on the hard-copy form for the 085 pit excavated on 19 May 1998
read "Only top 230 cm of 430 cm sampled. Total height [as determined with
probe] is 4 m 30 cm".
A note on the hard-copy form for the 084 pit excavated on 19 May 1998
read "Bottom Layer was mostly H20".
A note on the hard-copy form for the 088 pit excavated on 20 May 1998
indicated that an ice layer existed within the horizon from 60 cm to 70 
cm, and that there was and "underground stream" at ground level.
A note on the hard-copy form for the 006 pit excavated on 14 April 1998
indicated that no weights (and therefore masses, densities, and snow water
equivalences) were taken due to a broken scale.</para><para>
A note on the hard-copy form for the ssw pit excavated on 15 January 1999
indicated that the gound surface was unfrozen.
A note on the hard-copy form for the ssw pit excavated on 27 January 1999
indicated that the gound surface was unfrozen.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 17 March 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 7 April 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
-0.5 degrees C. Notes in comments section: "Ice layer", "Depth Hoar", 
"Stratigrafy data of questionable accuracy".  
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 14 April 1999
swn indicated that the surface temperature was -1.5 degrees C. 
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 21 April 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
-5 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 18 May 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 19 May 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 25 May 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 26 May 1999
at the location code 088 indicated that the surface temperature was
-1.0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 27 May 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C. Notes in comments section:"153,151,150 very distinct 
icelayers w/ ice and ET mixed in between." A note indicated that the
horizon 180-183 was saturated and that there was no data for this 
horizon. 
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 2 June 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C. "Saturated layer at soil surface."
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 3 June 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C. "Saturated layer just above ground, ground unfrozen". 
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 09 June 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C. "Saturated layer free water + Ice."  
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 10 June 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 5 June 1999
at the location code 006 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C. "Sat. layer (0-10)."   
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 17 June 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the surface temperature was
-1 degrees C. "Snow was poly..(??) from wet snow metamorphism.""Slush 
mud and meltwater for last 5cm." 
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 17 June 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the horizon 6-7 was 
"very wet (dripping)" 
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 31 March 1999
at the location code swn indicated that the surface temperature was
-3.5 degrees C. Horizon 0-27:"depth hoar", Horizon 27-54:"snow", 
Horizon 54-56:"ice", Horizon 56-66:"snow", Horizon 137-139:"snow", 
Horizon 139-148:"ice", Horizon 148-152:"snow", Horizon 152-154:"ice", 
Horizon 154-156:"snow", Horizon 156-161:"ice".  </para><para>
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 13 january 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-2.5 degrees C. "grains more rounded", "??????".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 14 january 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-6.5 degrees C. "Sight wind crust at surface".  
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 27 january 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-6 degrees C. The horizon 0-35 was "changing to ET".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 27 january 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-11 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 08 february 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-3 degrees C. Horizon 14-36 "formerly TG, cohesion less".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 17 February 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-4.5 degrees C. Horizon 108-110: "new snow".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 22 February 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-8.5 degrees C. The horizon 15-43 was "much less consolidated".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 24 February 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-6 degrees C. The horizon 105-114 had "sun crust".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 29 February 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Comments: "Add 4 degrees total temps!"  
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 2 March 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-7.5 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 7 March 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-1 degrees C. Horizon 0-10: "barely faceted", Horizon 10-40: "less 
consolidated layer" 
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 9 March 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-9 degrees C. Comments: "No grain size due to blowing snow".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 14 March 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-2 degrees C. Horizon 0-40 was "unconsolidated granular", Horizon 
159-161:"old surface crust granular".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 16 March 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-2 degrees C. Horizon 108-140: "fresh snow".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 21 March 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
-3.5 degrees C. Horizon 109-111: "old surface crust", Horizon 155-158:
"granular ice blobs old surface crust", Horizon 192-198: "granular,
old surface crust" Horizon 0-10: "this cut of snow had an animal's
burrow hole. A second cut yielded another smaller hole. I weighed
329g and the hole equated to ~3 grams of snow." 
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 28 March 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
-1 degrees C. Horizon 129-129: "new fallen snow, 1/4 cm".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 4 April 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 0-37: "more granular".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 10 April 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Comments: "CR=crust layer", "at 164 intermittent ice layer"
Horizon 145-146: "Intermittent ice layer crust" Horizon 0-43: 
"less consolidated".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 14 April 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 18 April 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 0-39: "less consolidated", Horizon 138-141: "This 
layer is intermittently an ice layer", Horizon 141-158: "There is an 
intermittent ice layer at 152-153".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 20 April 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 25 April 
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 27 April 
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Comments: "160 cm total depth 1103" "Fine day! Haze 
over Eastern Plains."   
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 2 May 
2000 at location code g4n indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.  
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 2 May 
2000 at location code g5n indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 2 May 
2000 at location code g5v indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 2 May 
2000 at location code 505 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 3 May  
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 3 May  
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 10 May  
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 0-3: "saturated".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 16 May  
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 40-98: "Intermittents ice layer at 71 and 54",
Horizon 108-113: "slush layer".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 19 May  
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 0-4: "slush layer".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 25 May  
2000 at location code swn indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 61-78: "couldn't find optic lens at saddle".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 25 May  
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 29 May  
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 0-13: "slush".
A note on the hard-copy data form for the pit excavated on 06 June  
2000 at location code 006 indicated that the suface temperature was
0 degrees C. Horizon 0-10: "slush", "MF=melt/freeze- rounded snow 
grains that have undergone wet metamorphism."  </para><para>
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 16 Jan 2001
at the location code 006 indicated that there was new snow.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 9 May 2001
at the location code g5n indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 9 May 2001
at the location code 088 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C. Comments: "Dirty ice layers at 110cm."
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 8 May 2001
at the location code 084 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 8 May 2001
at the location code 085 indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.
A note on the hard-copy form for the pit excavated on 9 May 2001
at the location code g5s indicated that the surface temperature was
0 degrees C.</para><para>
A note on the hard-copy form for the ssw pit measured 27 June 2011 
indicated that the pit was moved 2 m to the right.</para>
			</description>
		</methodStep>
	</methods>
<dataTable>
<entityName>snowprof.mw.data.csv</entityName>
	<entityDescription>Snow cover profile raw data for Niwot Ridge and Green Lakes Valley, 1993 - ongoing.</entityDescription>
<physical>
<objectName>snowprof.mw.data.csv</objectName>
<dataFormat>
<textFormat>
	<numHeaderLines>1</numHeaderLines>
	<numFooterLines>0</numFooterLines>
	<recordDelimiter>\r</recordDelimiter>
	<attributeOrientation>column</attributeOrientation>
	<simpleDelimited>
		<fieldDelimiter>,</fieldDelimiter>
		<quoteCharacter>"</quoteCharacter>
</simpleDelimited>
</textFormat>
</dataFormat>
	<distribution> 
		<online>
			<onlineDescription>Snow cover profile raw data for Niwot Ridge and Green Lakes Valley, 1993 - ongoing.</onlineDescription>
			<url function="download">http://niwot.colorado.edu/data_csvs/snowprof.mw.data.csv</url> 
		</online>
	</distribution>
</physical>
<attributeList>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>loc_code</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>loc_code</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>location code</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>string</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<nominal>
				<nonNumericDomain>
					<textDomain>
						<definition>location code</definition>
					</textDomain>
				</nonNumericDomain>
			</nominal>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>date</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>date</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>date</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>date</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<dateTime>
				<formatString>YYYY-MM-DD</formatString>
				<dateTimePrecision>1</dateTimePrecision>
				<dateTimeDomain>
					<bounds>
						<minimum exclusive="false">1993-02-26</minimum>
					</bounds>
				</dateTimeDomain>
			</dateTime>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>ht_bottom_horizon</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>ht_bottom_horizon</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>height of bottom of horizon above soil surface</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>float</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<ratio>
				<unit>
					<standardUnit>meter</standardUnit>
				</unit>
				<numericDomain>
					<numberType>real</numberType>
					<bounds>
						<minimum exclusive="false">0.00</minimum>
					</bounds>
				</numericDomain>
			</ratio>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>ht_top_horizon</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>ht_top_horizon</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>height of top of horizon above soil surface</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>float</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<ratio>
				<unit>
					<standardUnit>meter</standardUnit>
				</unit>
				<numericDomain>
					<numberType>real</numberType>
					<bounds>
						<minimum exclusive="false">0.00</minimum>
					</bounds>
				</numericDomain>
			</ratio>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>horizon_thickness</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>horizon_thickness</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>horizon thickness</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>float</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<ratio>
				<unit>
					<standardUnit>meter</standardUnit>
				</unit>
				<numericDomain>
					<numberType>real</numberType>
					<bounds>
						<minimum exclusive="false">0.00</minimum>
					</bounds>
				</numericDomain>
			</ratio>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>meas_wt</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>meas_wt</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>measured weight</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>integer</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<ratio>
				<unit>
					<standardUnit>gram</standardUnit>
				</unit>
				<numericDomain>
					<numberType>integer</numberType>
				</numericDomain>
			</ratio>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
	<attribute>
		<attributeName>meas_temp</attributeName>
		<attributeLabel>meas_temp</attributeLabel>
		<attributeDefinition>measured temperature</attributeDefinition>
		<storageType>float</storageType>
		<measurementScale>
			<ratio>
				<unit>
					<standardUnit>celsius</standardUnit>
				</unit>
				<numericDomain>
					<numberType>real</numberType>
					<bounds>
						<minimum exclusive="false">0.00</minimum>
					</bounds>
				</numericDomain>
			</ratio>
		</measurementScale>
		<missingValueCode>
			<code>NaN</code>
			<codeExplanation>missing</codeExplanation>
		</missingValueCode>
	</attribute>
</attributeList>
</dataTable>
</dataset>
</eml:eml>
